Diana Salas

Full stack web developer

Phone: (407) 576-9441 | Email: salasd10418@gmail.com | Largo, FL 33773

LinkedIn: /salasdi | Portfolio: salasd93.github.io | GitHub: /SalasD93

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer utilizing a background in social science to provide the best user experience for web application development. Earning a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from the University of Miami Coding Boot Camp. Adaptive problem-solver who loves to develop innovative software with focus on mobile-first design and development. Strengths in adaptability, detail-orientation, creativity, communication, problem-solving, teamwork, time-management, leadership, perseverance, and building projects from concept to completion.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages:

JavaScript ES6+, CSS3, HTML5, SQL

Applications:

GitHub, Heroku

Tools:

Git, JQuery, Bootstrap, Bulma, NodeJs, MySQL, Express, Handelbars.js, Inquirer, APIs, Sequelize, Tailwind, MongoDB, Mongoose ODM, MS Office

PROJECTS

IDK, You Pick | github.com/SalasD93/idk-you-pick | salasd93.github.io/idk-you-pick

- A random restaurant generator for people who are indecisive at mealtime.
- Role: Lead Developer
- Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bulma CSS, Server-side APIs

BookMe! | bookmebuyme.herokuapp.com | salasd93.github.io/bookme

- Summary: A used book selling app that allows users to interact based off location.
- Role: Co-developer
- Tools: NodeJS, Inquirer, MySQL, JavaScript, Express, Handlebars.js, HTML, CSS, Sequelize, Express Session

Track an Employee | github.com/Salasd93/track-an-employee | salasd93.github.io/track-an-employee

- Summary: Allows companies to manage employees through a command line accessed database.
- Role: Sole Developer
- Tools: NodeJS, Inquirer, MySQL, JavaScript

EXPERIENCE

Comfort Inn & Suites 2016-2017

Front Desk Agent Saint Petersburg, FL

Provided accommodations to guests from all countries and backgrounds in a high-paced, high-energy family-friendly hotel.

Key duties:

- Ran the front desk independently while taking and updating reservations via phone, email, and online platforms.
- Managed the in-house bar and convenience store during regular front desk shifts.
- Took charge of housekeepers and coordinated with them for hotel and guests' needs.
- Accommodated an average of 100 guests per shift.
- Utilized MS Excel to produce reports and keep track of inventory; MS Word to create letters for management and signs for various occasions; MS PowerPoint for corporate meetings.
- Collaborated with other employees to enhance the amount of work accomplished during a shift and to meet goals.
- Maintained communication with VA relations to accommodate medically needy veterans during VA trips for medical support; Relations with Bluegreen Vacations to accommodate their guests for their scheduled previews.
- Managed accommodations to leisure activities, restaurants, shopping, and transportation.

Department of Juvenile Justice

2013-2014

Juvenile Probation Officer Intern

Largo, FL

Worked with a team of probation officers in a fast-paced secured juvenile processing facility.

Key duties:

- Processed incoming juveniles for detainment
- Assessed juveniles for rehabilitation and diversion programs
- Input case information into the Juvenile Justice Information System
- Maintained files both physical and virtual
- Reviewed police reports for accuracy and information relevant to each case
- Attended court hearings for detained juveniles
- Managed juveniles on probation in collaboration with their probation officers

Publix Supermarkets 2011-2015

Customer Service/Grocery

Tampa, FL

Maintained exceptional customer service to all customers in a high-paced top-ranked grocery store.

Key duties:

- Maintained the highest possible level in evaluations (Role-model).
- Maintained the quickest register to provide the best experience for customers and maintain company efficiency while providing service to 100s of customers per shift.
- Assisted other employees in all areas of the store when they were short-staffed or behind on work.
- Maintained control of an entire grocery section while leveraging my time management skills to complete all necessary tasks and goals for the day.
- Collaborated with other team members to complete daily tasks and find the most efficient way to minimize time on any one task to get more accomplished than asked of us.
- Maintained inventory through spreadsheets, order forms, and other relevant software
- Collaborated with other employees to enhance the amount of work accomplished during a shift and to meet goals.
- Discussed issues and solutions with management to improve customer experience and employee productivity

EDUCATION

Certificate, Full Stack Web Development – University of Miami

Miami, FL

Associate of Science, Criminology and Criminal Justice – Hillsborough Community College

Tampa, FL

Accomplishments:

- Maintained Deans List
- Graduated with Honors
- Received multiple sportsmanship awards
- Obtained multiple leadership awards